<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<proof_reading_pro>
  <title>Grammar: More Plural Nouns</title>
  <directions>Find the errors. Select the word that needs to be changed or that needs punctuation after it. Then choose the proofreading symbol that will fix the error.</directions>
  <sfxPool value="pool1" />
  <rounds>
    <round>
      <sentences>
        <text>I think that {s|persons|people} today have easier {s|lifes|lives} than people did long ago. For example, {l}Food is more convenient. We can even plant pots of tomatoes on our {s|patioes|patios}. Also, {s|childrens|children} who live now have more time to play and do not have to work as hard.</text>
        <text>I am fascinated by ancient cultures. I often wonder how they chose their leaders. Did they grow foods we commonly eat today, such as {s|potatos|potatoes} and carrots{?|.} What role did {s|womans|women} play? I also try to imagine the different {s|animal|animals} that {s|person|people} had back then{,} but I am not sure if they had {s|sheeps|sheep}, horses, {s|gooses|geese}, or {s|ox|oxen}.</text>
      </sentences>
    </round>
    <round>
      <sentences>
        <text>Visiting Africa is an amazing experience! The amount of {s|wildlives|wildlife} is truly incredible. I saw a herd of red {s|deers|deer}, which are decreasing in numbers there. I am glad I took a lot of {s|photoes|photos}. I recommend the experience to {s|familys|families} considering an adventure for their next vacation{.}</text>
        <text>Sometimes you may see television shows that look like they take place in real living rooms, but they are actually filmed in TV studios. From the photos on the {s|pianoes|pianos} to the {s|fishes|fish} in the fishbowl, everything is a prop. The {s|wifes|wives} and {l}Husbands on the programs usually are not even related{.|?} As long as it does not seem fake{,} that is fine with me.</text>
      </sentences>
    </round>
    <round>
      <sentences>
        <text>Some people think it is fun to see horses at {s|rodeoes|rodeos}, but I prefer to watch them in a different setting. My {u}aunt Marta rides in jumping competitions. She is part of a team of {s|mans|men} and women who show their skill by guiding their horses over hurdles{.|,} {u}they look as though they are flying. When horses are not jumping, though, I am just as happy to watch them graze in fields and {s|vallies|valleys}.</text>
        <text>What has happened to the {s|buffaloes|buffalo}? Many {s|herd|herds} once roamed the prairie. Now there aren’t many of these animals{,} which are also known as {s|bisons|bison}, left. Native {u}american {s|tribe|tribes} once relied on the great beasts and ate only what they needed to survive. Over time, the tribes and European settlers began to kill the animals in greater numbers. Today there are many {s|group|groups} and organizations trying to protect the buffalo. I hope they are not too late.</text>
      </sentences>
    </round>
  </rounds>
</proof_reading_pro>

